I am an enthusiastic software engineer who has great interest in variety of emerging technologies, and more so on integrating / implementing them into useful products. I have had experience developing on multiple platforms such as Windows, Web / Mobile Apps, including implementation of REST APIs and database design. I also have experience and follow software development methodologies such as Agile / Scrum / TDD.

I aim to explore as many technologies and framework as possible to further my career options.

Education

Bachelor's Degree Industrial and Systems Engineering

National University of Singapore 2014 – 2018

Honors, Distinction

GCE 'A' Level Physics

Temasek Junior College 2012 – 2013

Skills



Experience

Software Engineer NUS

Jun 2018 - Present Singapore

Under the direct supervision of Professor Andrew Lim (Head, ISEM), I had a part in majority of the development projects; including web/mobile apps and backend services which are:

- NUS SUITE: A one-stop platform to manage all NUS apps to streamline day-to-day activities on campus. Opens a platform to submit self developed apps under NUS' own AppStore.
- NUS Maps: Get around campus with our new technology to direct you even to the exact room and floor. Options available include traveling via bus, pure walking, avoid stairs and only sheltered walkways.
- MINDEF IPPT App: Application that can be used to take IPPT at the comfort of your neighbourhood (by using state of the art image / video processing) instead of physically making a trip to the test center
- Indoor Outdoor Navigation Routing: Sourced ways to use WiFi fingerprinting / BLE / Natural Magnetic Fields to provide accurate indoor location, allowing Virtual NUS routing services to detect and provide directions with greater accuracy.
- Development of simulation based learning games to value add to the learnings of existing students everywhere. This project was developed entirely by myself including the back-end services (done on Node.JS (Express) / MongoDB and ASP.NET Core / MSSQL; handling Authorization, Error Logging, Unit / Integration Testing)

https://winegame.edventist.com

https://winegameadmin.edventist.com

Development of NUS Smart Dining App, including integration with payment systems such as NETS Pay, OCBC PayAnyone, DBS PayLah, Apple Pay etc. Exposed myself to creating image / text classification machine learning models and converting them to Core ML / TensorFlow Lite for object detection / recognition.

Student Researcher NUS

Apr 2018 – Jun 2018

Web API Development

UI/UX Design according to Project Requirements

Development of Web Apps using React.js

Development of iOS / Android Applications

Software Development Intern Arcstone Pte. Ltd.

Jun 2017 - Mar 2018

I've resumed my time with Arcstone to work on the following projects:

-WPF Maintenance tool to keep track of scheduled maintenance jobs and



Languages

English Native or bilingual

Mongolian Native or bilingual

Russian Limited working

schedule new maintenance jobs.

- -WPF Issues Manager tool to view and report new issues
 I've used the following new frameworks for these projects:
- -MVVM architectural pattern
- -Designing UI in accordance to Material Design framework by Google

Software Automation Engineer Intern Autodesk

Jan 2017 - Jun 2017 Solaris

As part of the Product Lifecycle Management Group under Vault, I am actively involved in various roles and projects including:

- Local and Remote Test Automations (Coded UI Tests)
- Product Maintenance
- Unit and Integration Testing

Skills acquired through my stay in Autodesk include, but not limited to:

- Familiarize with existing Autodesk Products, and not just AutoCad
- CI/CD (using Jenkins as the platform)
- Various Test Automation framework and platforms (Microsoft Test Agent, AutoIT etc)
- Industry wide used development practices (Scrum Meetings, Sprint Planning etc)
- Writing and maintaining functional, efficient test cases

Software Development Intern Arcstone Pte. Ltd.

Dec 2015 - Jan 2017

Throughout my time at Arcstone, I've initiated/completed, maintained and contributed to multiple projects with varying scales and scopes. Some of these includes:

- Database editor: Developed a Windows Application for intuitive database editing
- Arc.app: an iOS application that handles real-time data monitoring and workstation control

(Link: https://itunes.apple.com/sg/app/arc-app/id1205079950?mt=8)

- Web Api: the company's Web API for multiple usage: RESTful endpoint calls for arc.app and various other modules, cloud configurator for several modules, APIs for third-party integration

The skill sets that I've acquired through my time here:

- Vb.Net/C# development on the .NET framework, using DevExpress as UI extension
- Web API development
- Native Android development (Java/Android Studio)
- Native iOS development (Swift/Xcode)
- Database implementation/SQL
- Entity Framework for relational SQL databases

Programming intern I Travel Bold

Jun 2016 - Oct 2016

Through my internship at I Travel Bold, I have developed an iOS Application for travellers, allowing like minded travellers to meet and connect with each other.

This is where my interest to develop iOS applications took off, and I began exploring integrating various technologies with mobile apps.

Creator of Opportunities Detecq

Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

Detecq is an intelligent corporate-startup marketplace powered with proprietary algorithms to help companies accurately and efficiently discover their best strategic matches. As a private marketplace, Detecq provides a secure and discreet channel for corporates and startups to explore strategic partnership, investment, and exit opportunities.

As the creator of opportunities at Detecq, my main focus is to help tech startups and corporates connect with each other through this marketplace. This involves digital marketing, content marketing, social media marketing and event outreach to reach out to this parties